Shishir Gurung

Developer



720-419-4277

gurungsh@gmail.com

n linkedin.com/in/gurungsh

github.com/gurungsh

gurungsh.github.io

Versatile developer with about two years of professional experience in all phases of Software Development, from business requirement gathering to project delivery. Proficient in an assortment of technologies and methodologies. Able to effectively self-manage working as the sole developer, as well as collaborate in a team project.



Skills and Technologies

A/B Testing, Usability Testing, Waterfall Methodology, Agile Methodology, SCRUM, C#, ASP.Net, Java, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, XML, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ReactJS, SQL, PL/SQL, TSQL, JUnit, Team Foundation Server, Tortoise SVN, Ankh SVN, Tomcat, GitHub, Slack, Google Analytics



Education

Master of Science: Software Engineering

Regis University - Denver, CO

Graduated with 3.97 GPA

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Minnesota State University Moorhead - Moorhead, MN



Academic Project

Developed **Java** application "SchedulerApp" to aid Regis University students and advisers in building academic schedules. Web application powered by **REST web services** hosted on Amazon Web Services.

- Created service layer by implementing Interfaces.
- Implemented features of the application: create advisor or student

08/201<u>5 - 08/2017</u>

08/2010 - 12/2012

profile, create an academic schedule by applying the scheduler logic on a pre-defined course structure based on student's interest of specialization and passions.



Work History

02/2015 - 07/2015

Consultant

04/2015 - 05/2015

Vastika Inc., Dallas, TX

.Net Developer

Innovate Auto Finance, Fort Worth, TX

- Part of a two-man team to analyze if the company had resources and the need to rewrite Bulk Acquisition Tool (BAT).
- Played an active role in requirements gathering, analysis and design for the rewrite of BAT.
- Wrote an **XML** parser as a module of BATv5.
- Rewrote Stored Procedures and imported some of them to C# for clarity and programmability.
- After six weeks, we concluded that it was not feasible to rewrite BAT at that time.

10/2013 - 01/2015

Consultant

Pioneer Technologies Inc., Dallas, TX

.Net Developer

AAA Auto Insurance Mid-Atlantic, Mt. Laurel, NJ

- Worked both as a sole/full-stack developer and a productive team member in the company's Roadside Information and Membership applications.
- Played an active role in requirements gathering, analysis, design, development, debugging, performance tuning and testing **C#/ASP.Net** web applications.
- Experienced with both Waterfall and Agile Methodology (Scrum) as an active member during the transition of an application from Waterfall to Agile Methodology.
- Designed and developed two workflows for membership sign up for A/B testing.
- Optimized Stored Procedures by rewriting SQL queries in SQL Server Management Studio and PL/SQL Developer for performance.
- Used JavaScript libraries powered by FusionCharts to display Roadside Information as charts, create schedules and overtime signup for employees, and analyze service center performance.

10/2013 - 01/2015